<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Godot 3 on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/godot-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Godot 3 on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/godot-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot course: available content</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/godot/make-pro-2d-games/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/godot/make-pro-2d-games/content/</guid>
      <description>Last update: April 30
The course is still in early access, with currently six out of twelve chapters available in the Pro version.
The course comes in 3 versions. Each builds on top of the previous one and adds extra content:
 Hobby  (€ 14.95) Indie  (€ 29.95) Pro  (€ 59.95)  You&amp;rsquo;ll find some free tutorial samples below. I also released the Finite State Machine  demo open source, for the official Godot documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: small March update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</guid>
      <description>The new update is out! As announced in the last news post, it&amp;rsquo;s smaller than usual. for two reasons:
 I moved to Japan, took some time off and had a lot to do to settle down I caught a cold and worked slower than usual for the past 10 days. Over the past week I barely had any voice at all  Work has still been busy until the end of the month: it not only took a while to get back to everyone, catch up with activity on GitHub, but also to get back up to speed in a foreign country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course, tilesets update out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/01/godot-course-update-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 13:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/01/godot-course-update-4/</guid>
      <description>The 4th update of the Godot 3 course  is out! It includes the new tilesets and tilemap chapter, along with new videos to flesh out chapter 01.The character controller and chapter 08.Game pre-production.
Godot 3 just came out , and with some more work done on the official documentation and a nice collab with Mike from GameFromScratch, I will now focus my efforts fully on the course.
  The new website design by djrm looks gorgeous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot and Blender presentations from the Capitole du Libre 2017</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/back-from-the-capitole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:25:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/back-from-the-capitole/</guid>
      <description>Last week-end we went to the Capitole du Libre, a major event around Free Software in France, to showcase Godot. We met there with Gilles Roudière and Julian Murgia, two active contributors.
It was a busy event: even though there were fewer visitors than at FOSDEM, people kept coming to the Godot table, curious about the engine&amp;rsquo;s features.
Julian and Gilles gave a two-hours workshop based on @KidsCanCode&amp;rsquo;s Your first game  tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: Hobby and Indie versions out in early access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/godot-3-course-hobby-indie-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:29:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/godot-3-course-hobby-indie-out/</guid>
      <description>The new version is finally out! You will find improvements and an extra video in the Finite State Machine chapter, and a new Game Design chapter. This one includes 3 html-based course documents and 40 minutes of video.
The missing two versions of the course are now out on Gumroad:
 Hobby , for hobbyists with some game creation experience, who&amp;rsquo;d like a deeper dive in Godot 3 Indie , for independent developers and students  Disclaimer: I can&amp;rsquo;t produce videos for the main chapters until Godot 3 beta is out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 Close and Ranged Attack Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/godot-3-alpha-attack-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 08:10:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/godot-3-alpha-attack-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Last week we did a tutorial about attack mechanics in collaboration with Heartbeast. I got important feedback from you, the backers, and wanted to apply it to a self-contained tutorial. Consider it as a bonus while we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for Godot 3 beta.
Close combat attack:
 Weapon Animation  Weapon collision programming   Heartbeast&amp;rsquo;s tutorial:
 Ranged attack: fireball   It shows some of Godot&amp;rsquo;s strengths:
 Inherited scenes act as a base class that child scenes derive from, but you control it all through the editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for Godot 3: Why There Was No Course Update in September</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 09:03:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</guid>
      <description>Godot 3 is coming out much later than planned. Alpha 2 isn&amp;rsquo;t even out yet. This means breaking changes keep happening on the engine. In the past few weeks alone there were important improvements to 2D physics and the UI system. The devs even renamed _fixed_process to _physics_process. Today I finished a long UI design tutorial only to learn a new Layout menu just arrived.
   This tutorial will show you how to create a flexible GUI in Godot   If I produced gameplay programming videos now for the course, they&amp;rsquo;d soon become obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>