<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gdquest on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gdquest on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Course Kickstarter Next Monday</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to become a better game developer? Gdquest will be on Kickstarter next week, to fund the creation of a game creation course for the new Godot game engine. More precisely for Godot 3, which will be out this summer!
I’m doing it with the devs&amp;rsquo; support: Rémi (akien) followed the project since the very beginning and ensured the project will be as good as it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter, Your Feedback on the Form</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 13:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</guid>
      <description>More than 600 of you gave feedback on the Godot course&amp;rsquo;s Kickstarter! That&amp;rsquo;s close to 3 times as many as last time, for the Krita game art project. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what you had to say.
About the form&#39;s design There are 3 key questions you need to answer before you crowdfund a course: 1. Do enough people want it to happen? 2. Who are they? 3. What do they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Creation with Godot, Kickstarter soon</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 15:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Update: the form&amp;rsquo;s results are available: Check them out!
Back in December 2015, hundreds supported gdquest on Kickstarter to bring out game art tutorials to Krita. Since then, I produced more than a hundred videos for it, and the first professional game art course.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to go full time with GDquest. Back then there was no website, a small community, I had few contacts to help me and no experience with crowdfunding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct 2 tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:42:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</guid>
      <description>In a another life, I wrote a handful of tutorials for Construct 2. They&amp;rsquo;re not on this website anymore, but you can still find them on the engine&amp;rsquo;s official website.
Now, I make videos tutorials about game creation with free, open source game creation tools: learn more about GDquest.
Construct 2 tutorials:
 Grid-Based movement using the Tilemap object for collisions. Programming simple touch QTEs Quick Timer Events from a Game Design Perspective Top Down Jump - The Grasshopper How to design professional looking mobile game buttons 12 handy free productivity tools for game designers How to create a Radial Lifebar in Construct 2 How to Code Faster in Construct 2 My 7 best game design resources 4 productivity tricks with the event editor How to AI by example - Platform follower Drastically reduce your game&amp;rsquo;s download size with PNGquant How to simplify your AI code with Finite State Machines 3 techniques to manage complex UI with construct 2 How to do advanced callbacks in Construct 2 4 lessons learned from Dan the Rabbit How to improve your Construct 2 code with Callbacks Ceiling walk  Game art tutorials:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita game art course in early-access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</guid>
      <description>Update: the course is now out! Learn more below.
Do you want to become a better artist? To learn how professionals make beautiful sprites? Make professional painterly game art with Krita is a new premium training out in early access. It will show you how to make your own 2d game art with the open source painting program Krita.
It is available in 3 different versions to fit your budget and your very needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the office - January news</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:35:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</guid>
      <description>The past 2 months have been hectic. I’ll pass on the details, but since a few days, I’m renting an office. After so much time struggling to work from home, you can’t imagine how great it feels! I not only have access to the room 24/7, it’s also part of a local business incubator. The structure offer a lot of support, free training on accounting, management, legal stuff… All of which is quite complex in France.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>