<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gdquest on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gdquest on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 19:49:19 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Interface Design Course: standalone version</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/08/godot-ui-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 19:49:19 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/08/godot-ui-course/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the full Godot 3 course and you are only interested in UI design, you can now get our UI master series as a stand-alone course! That way you only pay for the content you want! 😊
This initial release contains 25 tutorials, for over 3h30 of content. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn to create:
 A pause menu and manage pause An inventory system you can use for any type of game An item menu inspired by old-school Japanese RPGs Animated lifebars and gauges that follow monsters in the game  Get the Godot UI Tutorial!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUI and Inventory tutorials: Godot course release 10</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/07/godot-course-update-user-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 15:39:19 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/07/godot-course-update-user-interface/</guid>
      <description>The UI course update is up! That&amp;rsquo;s the biggest monthly release to date 😊
These 3.5 hours of extra tutorials dedicated to Game User Interface will show you:
 How to separate the UI code from the gameplay, using the node tree, signals, and yield features How to design reusable UI components with Godot&amp;rsquo;s theme system How to create an inventory system and item menu  The first UI chapter is in both the Indie and Pro versions of the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot course release 9: particles!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 15:39:19 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-9/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s update adds 2 hours of tutorials dedicated to particles! There are now over 70 video tutorials in the course&amp;rsquo;s Pro version .
The particles chapter shows how to create a variety of effects like smoke and explosions. We start with the very basics and wrap-up with a fireball and layered visual effects.
If the first steps don&amp;rsquo;t change too much between effects, I wanted to show you tricks to build varied and complex effects with a small number of basic textures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender Power Sequencer 1.0 is out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/blender-power-sequencer-1.0-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 13:18:14 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/blender-power-sequencer-1.0-out/</guid>
      <description>Power Sequencer is a Free add-on to help Content Creators edit faster with Blender.
The add-on brings over 40 new core editing features to Blender, including:
 Instant import of your video footage, pictures, and audio Smart mouse-based tools to cut, trim, remove gaps&amp;hellip; Instant fades, crossfade to the next sequence Change the playback speed on the fly Instant render with presets  Get Power SequencerIt builds upon the great work done on the Blender Velvets and the VSEQF tools, in a project that gets continuous support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: the boss chapter is out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 18:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-7/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s update you get one new chapter in the course. This is the hardest and probably the biggest series I made so far: chapter 5 is dedicated to boss creation.
This builds upon chapters 1 to 3 and brings the state programming pattern  to everyone, whether you&amp;rsquo;ve got the essentials, the indie, or the pro version.
As the boss chapter took twice the time I planned to invest in it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the essentials version in May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: small March update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</guid>
      <description>The new update is out! As announced in the last news post, it&amp;rsquo;s smaller than usual. for two reasons:
 I moved to Japan, took some time off and had a lot to do to settle down I caught a cold and worked slower than usual for the past 10 days. Over the past week I barely had any voice at all  Work has still been busy until the end of the month: it not only took a while to get back to everyone, catch up with activity on GitHub, but also to get back up to speed in a foreign country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course, tilesets update out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/01/godot-course-update-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 13:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/01/godot-course-update-4/</guid>
      <description>The 4th update of the Godot 3 course  is out! It includes the new tilesets and tilemap chapter, along with new videos to flesh out chapter 01.The character controller and chapter 08.Game pre-production.
Godot 3 just came out , and with some more work done on the official documentation and a nice collab with Mike from GameFromScratch, I will now focus my efforts fully on the course.
  The new website design by djrm looks gorgeous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot course Christmas update: The character controller</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/12/godot-3-course-character-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 15:54:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/12/godot-3-course-character-controller/</guid>
      <description>The Christmas update of the Godot 3 course is out on Gumroad! It&amp;rsquo;s available in all early access versions of the course: Hobby, Indie and Pro.
Use the coupon code &amp;laquo;early&amp;raquo; to get 20% off while the course is in early access!
In this series, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to create a fairly robust character controller: we&amp;rsquo;re covering input, walk and run speed, handling collisions, adding a bump animation when the character hits something&amp;hellip; with a lot of techniques exposed along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for Godot 3: Why There Was No Course Update in September</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 09:03:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</guid>
      <description>Godot 3 is coming out much later than planned. Alpha 2 isn&amp;rsquo;t even out yet. This means breaking changes keep happening on the engine. In the past few weeks alone there were important improvements to 2D physics and the UI system. The devs even renamed _fixed_process to _physics_process. Today I finished a long UI design tutorial only to learn a new Layout menu just arrived.
   This tutorial will show you how to create a flexible GUI in Godot   If I produced gameplay programming videos now for the course, they&amp;rsquo;d soon become obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Course Kickstarter Next Monday</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to become a better game developer? Gdquest will be on Kickstarter next week, to fund the creation of a game creation course for the new Godot game engine. More precisely for Godot 3, which will be out this summer!
I’m doing it with the devs&amp;rsquo; support: Rémi (akien) followed the project since the very beginning and ensured the project will be as good as it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter, Your Feedback on the Form</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 13:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</guid>
      <description>More than 600 of you gave feedback on the Godot course&amp;rsquo;s Kickstarter! That&amp;rsquo;s close to 3 times as many as last time, for the Krita game art project. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what you had to say.
About the form&#39;s design There are 3 key questions you need to answer before you crowdfund a course: 1. Do enough people want it to happen? 2. Who are they? 3. What do they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Creation with Godot, Kickstarter soon</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 15:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Update: the form&amp;rsquo;s results are available: Check them out!
Back in December 2015, hundreds supported gdquest on Kickstarter to bring out game art tutorials to Krita. Since then, I produced more than a hundred videos for it, and the first professional game art course.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to go full time with GDquest. Back then there was no website, a small community, I had few contacts to help me and no experience with crowdfunding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct 2 tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:42:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</guid>
      <description>In a another life, I wrote a handful of tutorials for Construct 2. They&amp;rsquo;re not on this website anymore, but you can still find them on the engine&amp;rsquo;s official website.
Now, I make videos tutorials about game creation with free, open source game creation tools: learn more about GDquest.
Construct 2 tutorials:
 Grid-Based movement using the Tilemap object for collisions. Programming simple touch QTEs Quick Timer Events from a Game Design Perspective Top Down Jump - The Grasshopper How to design professional looking mobile game buttons 12 handy free productivity tools for game designers How to create a Radial Lifebar in Construct 2 How to Code Faster in Construct 2 My 7 best game design resources 4 productivity tricks with the event editor How to AI by example - Platform follower Drastically reduce your game&amp;rsquo;s download size with PNGquant How to simplify your AI code with Finite State Machines 3 techniques to manage complex UI with construct 2 How to do advanced callbacks in Construct 2 4 lessons learned from Dan the Rabbit How to improve your Construct 2 code with Callbacks Ceiling walk  Game art tutorials:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita game art course in early-access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</guid>
      <description>Update: the course is now out! Learn more below.
Do you want to become a better artist? To learn how professionals make beautiful sprites? Make professional painterly game art with Krita is a new premium training out in early access. It will show you how to make your own 2d game art with the open source painting program Krita.
It is available in 3 different versions to fit your budget and your very needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the office - January news</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:35:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</guid>
      <description>The past 2 months have been hectic. I’ll pass on the details, but since a few days, I’m renting an office. After so much time struggling to work from home, you can’t imagine how great it feels! I not only have access to the room 24/7, it’s also part of a local business incubator. The structure offer a lot of support, free training on accounting, management, legal stuff… All of which is quite complex in France.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>