<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gdquest on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gdquest on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter, Your Feedback on the Form</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 13:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than 600 of you&lt;/strong&gt; gave feedback on the Godot course&amp;rsquo;s Kickstarter! That&amp;rsquo;s close to 3 times as many as last time, for the Krita game art project. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what you had to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;About the form&#39;s design

There are 3 key questions you need to answer before you crowdfund a course:
1. Do enough people want it to happen?
2. Who are they?
3. What do they want?

To get to know people well, you need to ask a lot of things. However, everyone&#39;s busy, and in online forms, one abandons fast. That&#39;s why there were only 6 short questions, and only 3 mandatory ones. With that, I got a 60% completion rate, up from 45% last time. Aside from that, I chat with numerous people one on one to get detailed insights. Fellow content creators like Heartbeast, Godot devs, experienced teachers, and the community.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the results!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-all-starts-with-you&#34;&gt;It all starts with you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;76% said they&amp;rsquo;ll support the project on Kickstarter. The most common amounts people want to pledge are 10, 20, 40, 100 and 200 euros (&lt;em&gt;quartiles, median, 9th decile and 95 percentile values&lt;/em&gt;). That&amp;rsquo;s great news! The more funding, the longer the course will be.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/would-you-support.png&#34; alt=&#34;The picture shows 445 persons said they&amp;#39;d support the kickstarter&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        If that many people support the project, it&amp;#39;ll be funded for sure
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I can help you become better at game creation, but making a great course costs a lot of time. And time is money. Working full-time with open source technologies taught me how essential the community is, in many regards. That&amp;rsquo;s why such a project starts with &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making money isn&amp;rsquo;t hard in itself&amp;hellip; What&amp;rsquo;s hard is to earn it doing something worth devoting one&amp;rsquo;s life to
&lt;cite&gt;Carlos Ruiz Zafón&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-top-down-game&#34;&gt;A top-down game?&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/what-game-genre.png&#34; alt=&#34;Form results, showing 53% of the respondents prefer the project to be a Zelda-like, followed by Platformer&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I listed game genres that work well with a character, so we can explore movement and collisions in the course
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The 3 most popular types of games are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zelda-like (top-down)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platformer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RPG (turn-based)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected the platformer genre to take the first place. However, there are many tutorials about it already, and far less for other types of games. This might explain the results. Now it&amp;rsquo;s cool, because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to learn with top-down titles, even from the design&amp;rsquo;s standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the point of the course is not to teach you how to make a zelda-like, but to make you more capable with Godot and game creation in general. I just wanted to do that with a fun and appealing project. On top of that, a lot of what you&amp;rsquo;ll learn will apply directly to RPGs, covering 2 of the top 3 options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-style-50-50&#34;&gt;Learning style: 50/50&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/what-course-style.png&#34; alt=&#34;50% of the respondents want the course to be &#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        The answers in the &amp;#39;other&amp;#39; category show how torn people can be on the subject
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a different opinion on how things should be taught, but that&amp;rsquo;s the reflect of who we are: we all learn differently, and we&amp;rsquo;re all at different stages on our journey. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to make the course useful to every backer. There&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be step-by-step tutorials and code commentaries, to help new Godot users get more comfortable with the engine. But I&amp;rsquo;ll also cover more advanced topics for those who want to go a step further. I&amp;rsquo;ve already done that for the last project, and it worked well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-want-to-learn&#34;&gt;What you want to learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVERYTHING
&lt;cite&gt;The Godot community&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of the 502 requests, most are unique. And that&amp;rsquo;s normal. The key here is to spot the requests that are popular, tie in well into the course, and that are useful to everyone. I use them both to pick cool topics for free tutorials and to structure the course and Kickstarter campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to build the course with you, and I&amp;rsquo;ll improve the curriculum over time, based on your feedback. With these replies, I can better set priorities for the course and potential extra modules to add on top of it. For instance, a number of you want to know how to polish the game and manage animations (tweening, particles&amp;hellip;). To explain it properly, I need to cover some animation principles, theory, how it works in Godot, working with particles and special effects&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s so much to explain! But it&amp;rsquo;s more important to help you build solid foundations for your games first, so that&amp;rsquo;s the priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, there&amp;rsquo;ll be plenty for you to learn. And again, the higher the funding, the more bonus content you&amp;rsquo;ll get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-the-first-to-know&#34;&gt;Be the first to know!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know when the Kickstarter&amp;rsquo;s up, &lt;strong&gt;click the button below and subscribe to GDquest on Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;! You will get 1 free tutorial every single day throughout the campaign:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/c/gdquest&#34;&gt;
        &lt;button class=&#34;-calltoaction -success&#34;&gt;
            The GDquest channel
        &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time! Feel free to comment or ask questions below :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Creation with Godot, Kickstarter soon</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 15:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Update: the form&amp;rsquo;s results are available: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/&#34;&gt;Check them out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in December 2015, hundreds supported gdquest on Kickstarter to bring out game art tutorials to Krita. Since then, I produced more than a hundred videos for it, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-game-art-tutorial-1&#34;&gt;first professional game art course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to go full time with GDquest. Back then there was no website, a small community, I had few contacts to help me and no experience with crowdfunding. A lot had yet to be done. The Krita devs and I weren&amp;rsquo;t sure it would work, but it did. Fast forward 18 months, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to work hand-in-hand with the Godot developers to create the &lt;strong&gt;first premium course for the powerful Godot game engine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;godot-the-engine-you-ve-been-waiting-for&#34;&gt;Godot, the engine you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is certainly the most flexible, 100% Free and Open Source game engine out there. I mean, just look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://godotengine.org/features&#34;&gt;Godot&amp;rsquo;s key features&lt;/a&gt;. And in the upcoming version 3, there&amp;rsquo;s so much new stuff coming I&amp;rsquo;d need a separate article to just give you an overview of the changes. PBR workflow for 3d, light probes, audio mixer and audio effects, brand new asset management system, particles rebuilt from scratch&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/godot-editor-design.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Godot editor&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-one-thing-it-lacks&#34;&gt;The one thing it lacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Godot&amp;rsquo;s documentation is great and plenty of people made videos to get you started with it, there&amp;rsquo;s few high quality, structured tutorials to help you go further. I&amp;rsquo;m sure we could use a complete game creation course, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If over the past 3 years, nobody did it, there&amp;rsquo;s a good reason. This is not only months of full time work: it&amp;rsquo;s extremely risky for the teacher. Working full-time in open source technologies is risky. Money, or rather the lack of it, always gets in the way. Make a course for an open source program and you&amp;rsquo;ll earn far less than if you covered a big proprietary tool. You might not even get enough to put food on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-kickstarter-in-may&#34;&gt;On Kickstarter in May&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a professional designer. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in games for a few years now, made hundreds of videos, and I&amp;rsquo;m crazy enough to pave the road for future teachers. But I&amp;rsquo;ll need your help, because no one can work for months on such a project for free, me included. We&amp;rsquo;ve discussed that with Rémi (akien) at the first GodotCon, and the devs want this to happen. Actually, many of you want this to happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Kickstarter campaign will allow me to earn enough money to create high quality tutorials and to do a lot of communication around Godot, thus help new people learn about the engine. Tens of thousands have watched my Krita tutorials, and thousands stumble upon the videos every day. I&amp;rsquo;m working super hard now to wrap up freelance contracts, ongoing projects, and to live up to my words. I didn&amp;rsquo;t forget the channel, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t forget you guys.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gdquest.com/img/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/krita-course-cel-shading.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;3 stylized characters used to teach lighting fundamentals&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        I&amp;#39;m wrapping up a Krita course, out on May 9, to then focus on Godot
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Actually, during the campaign, I want to do a &lt;strong&gt;30 days, daily free tutorial challenge&lt;/strong&gt; about game design, programming with godot, and maybe a bit of game art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re interested in a premium course or not, this project is a positive step for Godot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a lot of communication for the Godot engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll make many free tutorials during the campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher quality education means more Godot power users, who can in turn help newcomers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional content can poke the interest of creators who would pass on the engine otherwise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I proved you&amp;rsquo;re ready to support a Godot instructor, other professional teachers will jump in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-want&#34;&gt;What do YOU want?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will focus on 2d game creation, because that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve got experience with. Then, I want to know what you want, so I can make a course that you&amp;rsquo;ll love!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so, please fill this short form (only 5 questions):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdquest.typeform.com/to/ul3bc1&#34;&gt;
        &lt;button class=&#34;-calltoaction -success&#34;&gt;
            Fill the form!
        &lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;want-to-know-when-it-starts&#34;&gt;Want to know when it starts?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscribe to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/c/Gdquest?sub_confirmation=1&#34;&gt;GDquest Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NathanGDquest&#34;&gt;GDquest on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know when it starts ASAP. Feel free to ask me questions! I&amp;rsquo;ll also share the results from the form when I&amp;rsquo;ve got everyone&amp;rsquo;s thoughts on the project :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time, and have a nice day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m doing now</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 19:57:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last update on April 9, 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am near Switzerland, in the French Alps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;m:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a mini game art series about cel shaded art with Krita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparing a Kickstarter campaign for a game design course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/post/2017/marketing/marketing-indie-games-with-0-budget/&#34;&gt;Writing articles&lt;/a&gt; as a freelancer to pay the bills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding a blender add-on to make videos efficiently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/&#34;&gt;GDquest Krita brushes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving this website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studying Japanese grammar and kanji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trail running and chinese boxing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occasionally writing hip-hop songs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing most of that, trying to make a living off my work so I can keep supporting open source game creators in a direct way: providing professional grade education for those tools, both paid and free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m open to opportunities, especially if you need somebody to create interesting tutorials. If you&amp;rsquo;re a fellow Youtuber, I love to do collab videos. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, motivating, and people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yVNOpMMbeNk&#34;&gt;seem to love that&lt;/a&gt;. So feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nathan@gdquest.com&#34;&gt;drop me an email&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct 2 tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:42:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a another life, I wrote a handful of tutorials for Construct 2. They&amp;rsquo;re not on this website anymore, but you can still find them on the engine&amp;rsquo;s official website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I make videos tutorials about game creation with free, open source game creation tools: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com&#34;&gt;learn more about GDquest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construct 2 tutorials:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/4838/grid-based-movement-using-the-tilemap-object-for-collisions&#34;&gt;Grid-Based movement using the Tilemap object for collisions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1445/programming-simple-touch-qtes&#34;&gt;Programming simple touch QTEs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1430/quick-timer-events-from-a-game-design-perspective&#34;&gt;Quick Timer Events from a Game Design Perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1405/top-down-jump-the-grasshopper&#34;&gt;Top Down Jump - The Grasshopper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1398/how-to-design-professional-looking-mobile-game-buttons&#34;&gt;How to design professional looking mobile game buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1388/12-handy-free-productivity-tools-for-game-designers&#34;&gt;12 handy free productivity tools for game designers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1377/how-to-create-a-radial-lifebar-in-construct-2&#34;&gt;How to create a Radial Lifebar in Construct 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1365/how-to-code-faster-in-construct-2&#34;&gt;How to Code Faster in Construct 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1323/my-7-best-game-design-resources&#34;&gt;My 7 best game design resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1275/4-productivity-tricks-with-the-event-editor&#34;&gt;4 productivity tricks with the event editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1158/how-to-ai-by-example-platform-follower&#34;&gt;How to AI by example - Platform follower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1154/drastically-reduce-your-games-download-size-with-pngquant&#34;&gt;Drastically reduce your game&amp;rsquo;s download size with PNGquant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1139/how-to-simplify-your-ai-code-with-finite-state-machines&#34;&gt;How to simplify your AI code with Finite State Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1085/3-techniques-to-manage-complex-ui-with-construct-2&#34;&gt;3 techniques to manage complex UI with construct 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1080/how-to-do-advanced-callbacks-in-construct-2&#34;&gt;How to do advanced callbacks in Construct 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1077/4-lessons-learned-from-dan-the-rabbit&#34;&gt;4 lessons learned from Dan the Rabbit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1063/how-to-improve-your-construct-2-code-with-callbacks&#34;&gt;How to improve your Construct 2 code with Callbacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1026/ceiling-walk&#34;&gt;Ceiling walk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game art tutorials:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1407/how-to-game-art-1-silhouettes&#34;&gt;How to game art #1 – Silhouettes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1410/how-to-game-art-2-drawing-game-assets&#34;&gt;How to game art #2 – Drawing game assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1412/how-to-game-art-3-drawing-with-selections-in-photoshop&#34;&gt;How to game art #3 – Drawing with selections in Photoshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1419/how-to-game-art-4-designing-a-cute-character&#34;&gt;How to game art #4 – Designing a cute character&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1426/how-to-game-art-5-the-principles-of-design&#34;&gt;How to game art #5 – The principles of design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1453/how-to-game-art-6-a-first-look-at-colors&#34;&gt;How to game art #6 - A first look at colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scirra.com/tutorials/1458/how-to-game-art-7-hue-shifting&#34;&gt;How to Game Art #7 - Hue Shifting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita game art course in early-access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Update: the course is now out! Learn more below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you want to become a better artist? To learn how professionals make beautiful sprites?&lt;/strong&gt; Make professional painterly game art with Krita is a new premium training out in early access. It will show you how to make your own 2d game art with the open source painting program Krita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is available in 3 different versions to fit your budget and your very needs. You&amp;rsquo;ll get 20% off your purchase with the coupon code &amp;laquo;early&amp;raquo; for the duration of the early access. Learn more below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gumroad.com/js/gumroad-embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;gumroad-product-embed&#34; data-gumroad-product-id=&#34;krita-game-art-tutorial-1&#34; data-outbound-embed=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/krita-game-art-tutorial-1&#34;&gt;Loading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://gdquest.com/product/krita/painterly-game-art/&#34;&gt;Access the Krita training&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only want to know when the course will be out, subscribe below and I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know via email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.gumroad-follow-form-embed button,.gumroad-follow-form-embed input{font-size:15px;font-family:-apple-system,&#34;.SFNSDisplay-Regular&#34;,&#34;Helvetica Neue&#34;,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;height:40px!important}.gumroad-follow-form-embed{zoom:1}.gumroad-follow-form-embed:after,.gumroad-follow-form-embed:before{display:table;line-height:0;content:&#34;&#34;}.gumroad-follow-form-embed:after{clear:both}.gumroad-follow-form-embed *{margin:0;border:0;padding:0;outline:0;box-sizing:border-box!important;float:left!important}.gumroad-follow-form-embed input{border-radius:4px 0 0 4px;line-height:20px;background:top right no-repeat #fff;border:1px solid #ddd;border-right:0;color:#aaa;padding:10px;box-shadow:inset 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,.02);text-rendering:optimizeLegibility;font-smoothing:antialiased;-webkit-appearance:none;-moz-appearance:caret;width:65%!important}.gumroad-follow-form-embed button{border-radius:0 4px 4px 0;box-shadow:0 1px 1px rgba(0,0,0,.12);-webkit-transition:all .05s ease-in-out;transition:all .05s ease-in-out;display:inline-block;padding:11px 15px 12px;cursor:pointer;color:#fff;line-height:100%;border:1px solid #31989d;filter:&#34;progid:DXImageTransform.Microsoft.gradient(startColorstr=#5ccfd4, endColorstr=#329ca1, GradientType=0)&#34;;background:-webkit-linear-gradient(top,#5ccfd4,#329ca1);background:linear-gradient(to bottom,#5ccfd4,#329ca1);width:35%!important}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;form action=&#34;https://gumroad.com/follow_from_embed_form&#34; class=&#34;form gumroad-follow-form-embed&#34; method=&#34;post&#34;&gt;&lt;input name=&#34;seller_id&#34; type=&#34;hidden&#34; value=&#34;6873367754130&#34;&gt; &lt;input name=&#34;email&#34; placeholder=&#34;Your email address&#34; type=&#34;email&#34;&gt; &lt;button data-custom-highlight-color=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;submit&#34;&gt;Sign up&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the office - January news</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:35:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/aouow3pfa7Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The past 2 months have been hectic. I’ll pass on the details, but since a few days, I’m renting an office. After so much time struggling to work from home, you can’t imagine how great it feels! I not only have access to the room 24/7, it’s also part of a local business incubator. The structure offer a lot of support, free training on accounting, management, legal stuff… All of which is quite complex in France. The building is great, and there are other entrepreneurs to share your thoughts and struggles with. Actually, the team in the office right in front of mine is into 3-D printing, and they are super nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it’s news time. In this month’s update, we talk about the weekly releases on the premium game art tutorial, the Godot tutorial series that’s happening right now on the channel, and FOSDEM and GodotCon, 2 events taking place from February 4 to 7. I’m going to give the Godot team a hand and prepare some upcoming project, so we can meet there! To get more details about all of that, I invite you to watch the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in February for the next update!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>