<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdfunding on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/crowdfunding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crowdfunding on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:18:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/crowdfunding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter: When and How you’ll get your Rewards</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/07/godot-kickstarter-rewards-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/07/godot-kickstarter-rewards-info/</guid>
      <description>You will get all your rewards, votes and major news via email, starting this week. So be sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve set the right address on Kickstarter. Feel free to send me a message on Kickstarter or an email if you have any trouble. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to:
 Add nathan[at]gdquest.com to your contacts Check your spam folder if you didn&amp;rsquo;t get anything on Sunday  When you will get your access keys Discord: check out the email you got to access the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Course Kickstarter Next Monday</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to become a better game developer? Gdquest will be on Kickstarter next week, to fund the creation of a game creation course for the new Godot game engine. More precisely for Godot 3, which will be out this summer!
I’m doing it with the devs&amp;rsquo; support: Rémi (akien) followed the project since the very beginning and ensured the project will be as good as it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter, Your Feedback on the Form</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 13:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</guid>
      <description>More than 600 of you gave feedback on the Godot course&amp;rsquo;s Kickstarter! That&amp;rsquo;s close to 3 times as many as last time, for the Krita game art project. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what you had to say.
About the form&#39;s design There are 3 key questions you need to answer before you crowdfund a course: 1. Do enough people want it to happen? 2. Who are they? 3. What do they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Creation with Godot, Kickstarter soon</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 15:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Update: the form&amp;rsquo;s results are available: Check them out!
Back in December 2015, hundreds supported gdquest on Kickstarter to bring out game art tutorials to Krita. Since then, I produced more than a hundred videos for it, and the first professional game art course.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to go full time with GDquest. Back then there was no website, a small community, I had few contacts to help me and no experience with crowdfunding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>