<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Krita Brushes on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/krita-brushes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Krita Brushes on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 08:42:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/krita-brushes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Cel Shaded 2d Characters With Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cel-shaded-2d-characters-with-krita/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 08:42:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cel-shaded-2d-characters-with-krita/</guid>
      <description>The second Krita game art tutorial series is out! Meet Pepper, Carrot, and cel shading. This course is based on the world of Pepper&amp;amp;Carrot, a webcomic under the CCBy 4.0 licence by David Revoy.
What you will learn  How to create game characters with a cartoon shaded art style Lighting and shading tricks with Krita  This is a short, yet a rich series. It comes with 14 video tutorials, plus a fully commented art time-lapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita Brushes Anniversary Update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/krita-brushes-anniversary-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 08:15:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/krita-brushes-anniversary-update/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a year already. 12 months, 12 consecutive updates. This anniversary release may not seem like much, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the biggest so far. I redesigned all the brushes from scratch! The new thumbnails are circular. That way, all the information they can convey is available whether you look at the pop-up palette or the presets list. The design is also unique so that it’s easy to differentiate from other bundles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Professional Painterly Game Art with Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/painterly-game-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 15:11:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/painterly-game-art/</guid>
      <description>What will I learn in this course?  How to make beautiful 2d game assets with a painterly style The process professionals follow, from the concept art to the finished assets Art fundamentals such as value and color contrast  On top of that, if you buy the premium version, you will get step by step exercise sheets and create your own game mockup, ready to use in the game engine of your choice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita Brushes For Game Artists</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/</guid>
      <description>Version 15 contains:
 83 unique brush presets 4 PDF documents to help you get started with the brushes Lifetime free updates  The premium tier adds:
 More than 30 minutes of exclusive video tutorials to get the most out of the brushes The natural media brushkit Priority support on Discord  Get the brushes    The new thumbnails in version 13   I take my time to design the presets and ensure that they are worth adding to the pack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>