<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 09:49:11 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender Power Sequencer 1.1 out: Faster edits ✂🎞</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/08/power-sequencer-1.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 09:49:11 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/08/power-sequencer-1.1/</guid>
      <description>Power Sequencer is our Free add-on to edit at the speed of thought with Blender&amp;rsquo;s Video Sequence Editor.
Version 1.1 improves the editing workflow with new features like:
 A cross-platform multithreaded renderer for the VSE, BPSRender, which fixes bugs existing scripts had A re-written tool to render proxies from videos, with a clear progress report Automatic smart selections for key tools when you don&amp;rsquo;t have anything selected  And more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Interface Design Course: standalone version</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/08/godot-ui-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 19:49:19 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/08/godot-ui-course/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the full Godot 3 course and you are only interested in UI design, you can now get our UI master series as a stand-alone course! That way you only pay for the content you want! 😊
This initial release contains 25 tutorials, for over 3h30 of content. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn to create:
 A pause menu and manage pause An inventory system you can use for any type of game An item menu inspired by old-school Japanese RPGs Animated lifebars and gauges that follow monsters in the game  Get the Godot UI Tutorial!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUI and Inventory tutorials: Godot course release 10</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/07/godot-course-update-user-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 15:39:19 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/07/godot-course-update-user-interface/</guid>
      <description>The UI course update is up! That&amp;rsquo;s the biggest monthly release to date 😊
These 3.5 hours of extra tutorials dedicated to Game User Interface will show you:
 How to separate the UI code from the gameplay, using the node tree, signals, and yield features How to design reusable UI components with Godot&amp;rsquo;s theme system How to create an inventory system and item menu  The first UI chapter is in both the Indie and Pro versions of the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot course release 9: particles!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 15:39:19 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-9/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s update adds 2 hours of tutorials dedicated to particles! There are now over 70 video tutorials in the course&amp;rsquo;s Pro version .
The particles chapter shows how to create a variety of effects like smoke and explosions. We start with the very basics and wrap-up with a fireball and layered visual effects.
If the first steps don&amp;rsquo;t change too much between effects, I wanted to show you tricks to build varied and complex effects with a small number of basic textures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender Power Sequencer 1.0 is out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/blender-power-sequencer-1.0-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 13:18:14 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/blender-power-sequencer-1.0-out/</guid>
      <description>Power Sequencer is a Free add-on to help Content Creators edit faster with Blender.
The add-on brings over 40 new core editing features to Blender, including:
 Instant import of your video footage, pictures, and audio Smart mouse-based tools to cut, trim, remove gaps&amp;hellip; Instant fades, crossfade to the next sequence Change the playback speed on the fly Instant render with presets  Get Power SequencerIt builds upon the great work done on the Blender Velvets and the VSEQF tools, in a project that gets continuous support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: the boss chapter is out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 18:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-7/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s update you get one new chapter in the course. This is the hardest and probably the biggest series I made so far: chapter 5 is dedicated to boss creation.
This builds upon chapters 1 to 3 and brings the state programming pattern  to everyone, whether you&amp;rsquo;ve got the essentials, the indie, or the pro version.
As the boss chapter took twice the time I planned to invest in it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the essentials version in May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: small March update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</guid>
      <description>The new update is out! As announced in the last news post, it&amp;rsquo;s smaller than usual. for two reasons:
 I moved to Japan, took some time off and had a lot to do to settle down I caught a cold and worked slower than usual for the past 10 days. Over the past week I barely had any voice at all  Work has still been busy until the end of the month: it not only took a while to get back to everyone, catch up with activity on GitHub, but also to get back up to speed in a foreign country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course, tilesets update out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/01/godot-course-update-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 13:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/01/godot-course-update-4/</guid>
      <description>The 4th update of the Godot 3 course  is out! It includes the new tilesets and tilemap chapter, along with new videos to flesh out chapter 01.The character controller and chapter 08.Game pre-production.
Godot 3 just came out , and with some more work done on the official documentation and a nice collab with Mike from GameFromScratch, I will now focus my efforts fully on the course.
  The new website design by djrm looks gorgeous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot course Christmas update: The character controller</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/12/godot-3-course-character-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 15:54:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/12/godot-3-course-character-controller/</guid>
      <description>The Christmas update of the Godot 3 course is out on Gumroad! It&amp;rsquo;s available in all early access versions of the course: Hobby, Indie and Pro.
Use the coupon code &amp;laquo;early&amp;raquo; to get 20% off while the course is in early access!
In this series, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to create a fairly robust character controller: we&amp;rsquo;re covering input, walk and run speed, handling collisions, adding a bump animation when the character hits something&amp;hellip; with a lot of techniques exposed along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot and Blender presentations from the Capitole du Libre 2017</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/back-from-the-capitole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:25:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/back-from-the-capitole/</guid>
      <description>Last week-end we went to the Capitole du Libre, a major event around Free Software in France, to showcase Godot. We met there with Gilles Roudière and Julian Murgia, two active contributors.
It was a busy event: even though there were fewer visitors than at FOSDEM, people kept coming to the Godot table, curious about the engine&amp;rsquo;s features.
Julian and Gilles gave a two-hours workshop based on @KidsCanCode&amp;rsquo;s Your first game  tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: Hobby and Indie versions out in early access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/godot-3-course-hobby-indie-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:29:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/godot-3-course-hobby-indie-out/</guid>
      <description>The new version is finally out! You will find improvements and an extra video in the Finite State Machine chapter, and a new Game Design chapter. This one includes 3 html-based course documents and 40 minutes of video.
The missing two versions of the course are now out on Gumroad:
 Hobby , for hobbyists with some game creation experience, who&amp;rsquo;d like a deeper dive in Godot 3 Indie , for independent developers and students  Disclaimer: I can&amp;rsquo;t produce videos for the main chapters until Godot 3 beta is out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 Close and Ranged Attack Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/godot-3-alpha-attack-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 08:10:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/godot-3-alpha-attack-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Last week we did a tutorial about attack mechanics in collaboration with Heartbeast. I got important feedback from you, the backers, and wanted to apply it to a self-contained tutorial. Consider it as a bonus while we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for Godot 3 beta.
Close combat attack:
 Weapon Animation  Weapon collision programming   Heartbeast&amp;rsquo;s tutorial:
 Ranged attack: fireball   It shows some of Godot&amp;rsquo;s strengths:
 Inherited scenes act as a base class that child scenes derive from, but you control it all through the editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for Godot 3: Why There Was No Course Update in September</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 09:03:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</guid>
      <description>Godot 3 is coming out much later than planned. Alpha 2 isn&amp;rsquo;t even out yet. This means breaking changes keep happening on the engine. In the past few weeks alone there were important improvements to 2D physics and the UI system. The devs even renamed _fixed_process to _physics_process. Today I finished a long UI design tutorial only to learn a new Layout menu just arrived.
   This tutorial will show you how to create a flexible GUI in Godot   If I produced gameplay programming videos now for the course, they&amp;rsquo;d soon become obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter: When and How you’ll get your Rewards</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/07/godot-kickstarter-rewards-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/07/godot-kickstarter-rewards-info/</guid>
      <description>You will get all your rewards, votes and major news via email, starting this week. So be sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve set the right address on Kickstarter. Feel free to send me a message on Kickstarter or an email if you have any trouble. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to:
 Add nathan[at]gdquest.com to your contacts Check your spam folder if you didn&amp;rsquo;t get anything on Sunday  When you will get your access keys Discord: check out the email you got to access the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Professional 2d Games with Godot: Kickstarter LIVE</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/2d-games-godot-kickstarter-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 12:00:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/2d-games-godot-kickstarter-live/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make the first professional 2-D game creation course for the Godot game engine a reality! The Kickstarter is now live. The higher the funding goes, the more content you will get. Every single cent will go to the project.
On top of that, for the next 30 days, you will get a free tutorial every day on YouTube.
Learn to create your own 2d game inspired by Zelda! Back the Kickstarter now and get at least 50% of final course&amp;rsquo;s price!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Course Kickstarter Next Monday</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to become a better game developer? Gdquest will be on Kickstarter next week, to fund the creation of a game creation course for the new Godot game engine. More precisely for Godot 3, which will be out this summer!
I’m doing it with the devs&amp;rsquo; support: Rémi (akien) followed the project since the very beginning and ensured the project will be as good as it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Krita Game Art Course Out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cartoon-game-characters-krita-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cartoon-game-characters-krita-out/</guid>
      <description>The second premium Krita game art course, Make Cel Shaded Game Characters, is out! It contains 14 tutorials that will help you improve your lighting fundamentals and show you how to make a game character.
Get the course now!The course is based on Pepper and Carrot, the main 2 characters of a webcomic by David Revoy. It&amp;rsquo;s available under the CC-By 4.0 licence. It&amp;rsquo;s very common to work on an existing IP or world as a game artist, and David&amp;rsquo;s comic allows us to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter, Your Feedback on the Form</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 13:37:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-form-results/</guid>
      <description>More than 600 of you gave feedback on the Godot course&amp;rsquo;s Kickstarter! That&amp;rsquo;s close to 3 times as many as last time, for the Krita game art project. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at what you had to say.
About the form&#39;s design There are 3 key questions you need to answer before you crowdfund a course: 1. Do enough people want it to happen? 2. Who are they? 3. What do they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Cel Shaded 2d Characters With Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cel-shaded-2d-characters-with-krita/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 08:42:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cel-shaded-2d-characters-with-krita/</guid>
      <description>The second Krita game art tutorial series is out! Meet Pepper, Carrot, and cel shading. This course is based on the world of Pepper&amp;amp;Carrot, a webcomic under the CCBy 4.0 licence by David Revoy.
What you will learn  How to create game characters with a cartoon shaded art style Lighting and shading tricks with Krita  This is a short, yet a rich series. It comes with 14 video tutorials, plus a fully commented art time-lapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita Brushes Anniversary Update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/krita-brushes-anniversary-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 08:15:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/krita-brushes-anniversary-update/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a year already. 12 months, 12 consecutive updates. This anniversary release may not seem like much, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the biggest so far. I redesigned all the brushes from scratch! The new thumbnails are circular. That way, all the information they can convey is available whether you look at the pop-up palette or the presets list. The design is also unique so that it’s easy to differentiate from other bundles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Creation with Godot, Kickstarter soon</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 15:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-engine-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>Update: the form&amp;rsquo;s results are available: Check them out!
Back in December 2015, hundreds supported gdquest on Kickstarter to bring out game art tutorials to Krita. Since then, I produced more than a hundred videos for it, and the first professional game art course.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to go full time with GDquest. Back then there was no website, a small community, I had few contacts to help me and no experience with crowdfunding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Professional Game Art with Krita out now!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/first-krita-course-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 13:06:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/first-krita-course-out/</guid>
      <description>After months of work, the Make Professional Painterly Game Art with Krita course is out!
It&amp;rsquo;s the first and only Krita course about 2d game art. I took the time to explain the workflow and techniques I use in my work as a professional designer.
In this course, you will learn:
 How to create smart, reusable game sprites How to make your own game characters and environment You will improve your art fundamentals (Pro and Premium) You will acquire new tricks to work efficiently with Krita (Pro and Premium)  What&amp;rsquo;s in it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing indie games with no budget – Notes</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/marketing/marketing-indie-games-with-0-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:33:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/marketing/marketing-indie-games-with-0-budget/</guid>
      <description>Emmy Jonhassen, aka IndieGameGirl, gave a talk named Marketing Indie Games on a $0 Budget. It offers a nice introduction to the topic, so I decided to share synthetic notes for it.
I also wrote a detailed article on the topic for Game Analytics. There, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot more about everything I&amp;rsquo;ve outlined below. Check it out: Marketing Your Indie Game On A Zero-Dollar Budget
Emmy outlines 5 key types of contents required to maximize your game’s reach before and after its release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita game art course in early-access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</guid>
      <description>Update: the course is now out! Learn more below.
Do you want to become a better artist? To learn how professionals make beautiful sprites? Make professional painterly game art with Krita is a new premium training out in early access. It will show you how to make your own 2d game art with the open source painting program Krita.
It is available in 3 different versions to fit your budget and your very needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the office - January news</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:35:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</guid>
      <description>The past 2 months have been hectic. I’ll pass on the details, but since a few days, I’m renting an office. After so much time struggling to work from home, you can’t imagine how great it feels! I not only have access to the room 24/7, it’s also part of a local business incubator. The structure offer a lot of support, free training on accounting, management, legal stuff… All of which is quite complex in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from japan, back to work</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/back-from-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 20:16:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/back-from-japan/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I’m back from Japan! Physically at least: my heart is still back there. I’ve been traveling around the country for a bit less than a month, and the experience was incredible. It was a great occasion to practice Japanese and get a better sense for the culture. I’ve read and been told a lot of things before going, and reality felt a lot subtler than what you would expect at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Art Quest vol1 done! Off to Japan</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/japan-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 08:24:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/japan-news/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the first volume of Game Art Quest is done. 6.2 hours of free Krita tutorials (some are still upcoming on the channel). 7 hours if you include the first bonus series of the year: Introduction to monster design for 2-D games. Looking back at the Kickstarter description, this is already more than the promised as far as the total length is concerned.
 Early access  Available tutorials (free)  The extra premium brushes and their companion tutorials are also getting pretty big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/summer-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 13:49:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/summer-news/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since the last behind the scenes news post. There&amp;rsquo;s been good progress with the tutorials and the brushes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been hard at work lately, especially changing my workflow to increase production speed, maintaining the same quality. On the other hand, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to update the website and social networks as often as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked. Aside from that&amp;hellip;
Krita 3.0.1 is out! Krita 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June update: the Randa meetings</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/kickstarter-news-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 11:17:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/kickstarter-news-june/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re getting to the end of June. It&amp;rsquo;s time to sum up all that&amp;rsquo;s been happening this month. The short version: I kept improving the website, went to the biggest yearly KDE development sprint in Randa, Switzerland, and added about 1h of tutorials dedicated to Krita 3&amp;rsquo;s new features in the Krita training. You can find more details about what happened in Randa, and what the plans are for July, below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May update: Krita brushes and ConciseCSS</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 13:11:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/new-website-and-krita-brushes-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May has been a busy month. I did my best to keep up with everyone on social networks, to give a hand to the Krita developers, with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjIiI8uiVNM&#34;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; But I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to write longer news posts like this one. Time to share the news for this month! &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Krita 3.0? Krita Review</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/krita/new-features-in-krita-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 17:49:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/krita/new-features-in-krita-3/</guid>
      <description>Never heard of Krita? It is a free, open source digital painting program that used to be Linux-only. Since 2 years though, there&amp;rsquo;s a Windows version, and the program is now being ported to Mac.
Krita 3 is a major update to an already powerful application. It brings it to a whole new level. It ships with a new rendering engine, a traditional animation toolset, an overhauled layers docker, rulers, grid, guides, snapping support, and a brand-new tablet code, which supports more Wacom alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Tips: Concatenate paths with variables</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/programming/hugo-tips-concat-node-paths-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 09:34:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/programming/hugo-tips-concat-node-paths-variable/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial is a post I initially wrote on the Hugo forums. Hugo is the static website generator that powers GDquest. It is a really flexible and elegant system, based on Google&amp;rsquo;s Go programming language. Sometimes, it is a bit hard to use for a non-tech-savvy user. So I decided to share some tips on things that got me stuck at some point. 
In a template, you sometimes need to load data from a path based on a parameter in your content file’s front matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended graphic tablets</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/krita/recommended-graphic-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/krita/recommended-graphic-tablets/</guid>
      <description>Recommended graphic tablets On this page, you can find a list of the graphic tablets I recommend for Game Art Quest. I used Frenden&amp;rsquo;s reviews as a reference to pick affordable tablets you can try out. I also asked feedback to fellow professionals who use Huion devices, as I only have Wacom tablets here. When you buy a graphic tablet, be sure to test your device and to use your right of withdrawal in case you don&amp;rsquo;t like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDquest news and Krita 3.0 pre-alpha 3</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/community/gdquest-news-and-krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:25:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/community/gdquest-news-and-krita-3.0-pre-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I wanted to keep you posted on what is going on right now with GDquest. The video says it all, but I’m going to sum up the news below.
With one last contract finished last week, and the series on monster design done, I am now working full-time on Game Art Quest. My top priority is to release the first version of the GAQ Krita brush back and to finish chapter 0 in the training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for future free tutorials! 2016</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 09:16:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/community/vote-for-upcoming-tutorials-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>06-2016 update: Voting is over! You were more than 400 to vote on the series you want to see on GDquest.
Here are the top 3 results:
 Overview of Godot 2 (249 votes) Painting rock and grass tiles for 2d games (141 votes) Human proportions, from reality to games (119 votes)  Let your voice be heard Up until now, the tutorials have been a bit random on GDquest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phaser auto completion in Atom</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/programming/phaser-auto-completion-in-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/programming/phaser-auto-completion-in-atom/</guid>
      <description>This little guide will show you how to use the tern-phaser plugin by Angelo with Atom.
Installing tern This first part explains how to get npm, install tern and the tern-phaser plugin. The first thing that you need to ensure is that you have Node.js installed on your computer. You can download it on https://nodejs.org/en/. This will give you access to npm as well, a handy package manager for js libraries and plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>