<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gdquest News on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gdquest News on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 08:42:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/gdquest-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Cel Shaded 2d Characters With Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cel-shaded-2d-characters-with-krita/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 08:42:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cel-shaded-2d-characters-with-krita/</guid>
      <description>The second Krita game art tutorial series is out! Meet Pepper, Carrot, and cel shading. This course is based on the world of Pepper&amp;amp;Carrot, a webcomic under the CCBy 4.0 licence by David Revoy.
What you will learn  How to create game characters with a cartoon shaded art style Lighting and shading tricks with Krita  This is a short, yet a rich series. It comes with 14 video tutorials, plus a fully commented art time-lapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita Brushes Anniversary Update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/krita-brushes-anniversary-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 08:15:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/krita-brushes-anniversary-update/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a year already. 12 months, 12 consecutive updates. This anniversary release may not seem like much, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly the biggest so far. I redesigned all the brushes from scratch! The new thumbnails are circular. That way, all the information they can convey is available whether you look at the pop-up palette or the presets list. The design is also unique so that it’s easy to differentiate from other bundles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Professional Game Art with Krita out now!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/first-krita-course-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 13:06:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/first-krita-course-out/</guid>
      <description>After months of work, the Make Professional Painterly Game Art with Krita course is out!
It&amp;rsquo;s the first and only Krita course about 2d game art. I took the time to explain the workflow and techniques I use in my work as a professional designer.
In this course, you will learn:
 How to create smart, reusable game sprites How to make your own game characters and environment You will improve your art fundamentals (Pro and Premium) You will acquire new tricks to work efficiently with Krita (Pro and Premium)  What&amp;rsquo;s in it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m doing now</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 19:57:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/now/</guid>
      <description>Last update on April 9, 2017
I am near Switzerland, in the French Alps.
Lately, I&amp;rsquo;m:
 Building a mini game art series about cel shaded art with Krita Preparing a Kickstarter campaign for a game design course Writing articles as a freelancer to pay the bills Coding a blender add-on to make videos efficiently Working on the GDquest Krita brushes Improving this website Studying Japanese grammar and kanji Trail running and chinese boxing Occasionally writing hip-hop songs  I&amp;rsquo;m doing most of that, trying to make a living off my work so I can keep supporting open source game creators in a direct way: providing professional grade education for those tools, both paid and free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct 2 tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:42:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</guid>
      <description>In a another life, I wrote a handful of tutorials for Construct 2. They&amp;rsquo;re not on this website anymore, but you can still find them on the engine&amp;rsquo;s official website.
Now, I make videos tutorials about game creation with free, open source game creation tools: learn more about GDquest.
Construct 2 tutorials:
 Grid-Based movement using the Tilemap object for collisions. Programming simple touch QTEs Quick Timer Events from a Game Design Perspective Top Down Jump - The Grasshopper How to design professional looking mobile game buttons 12 handy free productivity tools for game designers How to create a Radial Lifebar in Construct 2 How to Code Faster in Construct 2 My 7 best game design resources 4 productivity tricks with the event editor How to AI by example - Platform follower Drastically reduce your game&amp;rsquo;s download size with PNGquant How to simplify your AI code with Finite State Machines 3 techniques to manage complex UI with construct 2 How to do advanced callbacks in Construct 2 4 lessons learned from Dan the Rabbit How to improve your Construct 2 code with Callbacks Ceiling walk  Game art tutorials:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita game art course in early-access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/gaq-early-access/</guid>
      <description>Update: the course is now out! Learn more below.
Do you want to become a better artist? To learn how professionals make beautiful sprites? Make professional painterly game art with Krita is a new premium training out in early access. It will show you how to make your own 2d game art with the open source painting program Krita.
It is available in 3 different versions to fit your budget and your very needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the office - January news</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 17:35:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/in-the-office/</guid>
      <description>The past 2 months have been hectic. I’ll pass on the details, but since a few days, I’m renting an office. After so much time struggling to work from home, you can’t imagine how great it feels! I not only have access to the room 24/7, it’s also part of a local business incubator. The structure offer a lot of support, free training on accounting, management, legal stuff… All of which is quite complex in France.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>