<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Krita 3 on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/krita-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Krita 3 on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/krita-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Krita Game Art Course Out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cartoon-game-characters-krita-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/make-cartoon-game-characters-krita-out/</guid>
      <description>The second premium Krita game art course, Make Cel Shaded Game Characters, is out! It contains 14 tutorials that will help you improve your lighting fundamentals and show you how to make a game character.
Get the course now! The course is based on Pepper and Carrot, the main 2 characters of a webcomic by David Revoy. It&amp;rsquo;s available under the CC-By 4.0 licence. It&amp;rsquo;s very common to work on an existing IP or world as a game artist, and David&amp;rsquo;s comic allows us to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Cel Shaded 2d Characters With Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/cel-shading-for-characters-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/cel-shading-for-characters-course/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial series will show you how to create your own game characters from scratch. It is based on the webcomic Pepper and Carrot by David Revoy.
What you will learn  How to create game characters with a cartoon shaded art style Lighting and shading tricks with Krita  This is a short, yet a rich series. It comes with 14 video tutorials, plus a fully commented art time-lapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in Krita 3.0? Krita Review</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/krita/new-features-in-krita-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 17:49:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2016/krita/new-features-in-krita-3/</guid>
      <description>Never heard of Krita? It is a free, open source digital painting program that used to be Linux-only. Since 2 years though, there&amp;rsquo;s a Windows version, and the program is now being ported to Mac.
Krita 3 is a major update to an already powerful application. It brings it to a whole new level. It ships with a new rendering engine, a traditional animation toolset, an overhauled layers docker, rulers, grid, guides, snapping support, and a brand-new tablet code, which supports more Wacom alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>