<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Olds on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/old/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Olds on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:42:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/old/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Construct 2 tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:42:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/old/construct-2/</guid>
      <description>In a another life, I wrote a handful of tutorials for Construct 2. They&amp;rsquo;re not on this website anymore, but you can still find them on the engine&amp;rsquo;s official website.
Now, I make videos tutorials about game creation with free, open source game creation tools: learn more about GDquest.
Construct 2 tutorials:
 Grid-Based movement using the Tilemap object for collisions. Programming simple touch QTEs Quick Timer Events from a Game Design Perspective Top Down Jump - The Grasshopper How to design professional looking mobile game buttons 12 handy free productivity tools for game designers How to create a Radial Lifebar in Construct 2 How to Code Faster in Construct 2 My 7 best game design resources 4 productivity tricks with the event editor How to AI by example - Platform follower Drastically reduce your game&amp;rsquo;s download size with PNGquant How to simplify your AI code with Finite State Machines 3 techniques to manage complex UI with construct 2 How to do advanced callbacks in Construct 2 4 lessons learned from Dan the Rabbit How to improve your Construct 2 code with Callbacks Ceiling walk  Game art tutorials:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>