<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Products on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/product/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Products on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/product/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita brushes update 14 - release notes</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/version-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/version-14/</guid>
      <description>The new release of the GDquest Krita brushes comes with 4 vegetation presets. In the past year, I learned a lot about Krita&amp;rsquo;s brush engines, its strengths and limitations. I also tried to release a lot of presets to stuff up the pack. It&amp;rsquo;s now time to slow down, and improve the releases. Starting with this one, the focus is on quality over quantity.
The new presets are all documented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Cel Shaded 2d Characters With Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/cel-shading-for-characters-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/cel-shading-for-characters-course/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial series will show you how to create your own game characters from scratch. It is based on the webcomic Pepper and Carrot by David Revoy.
What you will learn  How to create game characters with a cartoon shaded art style Lighting and shading tricks with Krita  This is a short, yet a rich series. It comes with 14 video tutorials, plus a fully commented art time-lapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Professional Painterly Game Art with Krita</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/painterly-game-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 15:11:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/painterly-game-art/</guid>
      <description>What will I learn in this course?  How to make beautiful 2d game assets with a painterly style The process professionals follow, from the concept art to the finished assets Art fundamentals such as value and color contrast  On top of that, if you buy the premium version, you will get step by step exercise sheets and create your own game mockup, ready to use in the game engine of your choice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krita Brushes For Game Artists</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/krita/brushes/</guid>
      <description>Version 13 (April 2017) contains:
 73 unique brush presets 2 pdf documents to help you get started with the brushes Monthly updates. More brushes and videos are already on your way! Completely redesigned thumbnails  The premium tier adds:
 More than 30 minutes of exclusive video tutorials to get the most out of the brushes The natural media brushkit Priority support    The new thumbnails in version 13   I take my time to design the presets and ensure that they are worth adding to the pack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>