<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gamedev on GDQuest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/gamedev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gamedev on GDQuest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/gamedev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>make professional 2d games with godot</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/product/godot/make-pro-2d-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/product/godot/make-pro-2d-games/</guid>
      <description>Become a better game developer! With this course, you will learn to create the main mechanics and systems in your own games, using the Free Godot Game Engine.
Unlike in many beginner courses that show how to code a specific game step-by-step, this one will teach you professional game creation techniques you can apply to any type of game!
 Purchasing the Pro course is the best investment I have made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: the boss chapter is out!</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 18:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/06/godot-course-update-7/</guid>
      <description>In this month&amp;rsquo;s update you get one new chapter in the course. This is the hardest and probably the biggest series I made so far: chapter 5 is dedicated to boss creation.
This builds upon chapters 1 to 3 and brings the state programming pattern  to everyone, whether you&amp;rsquo;ve got the essentials, the indie, or the pro version.
As the boss chapter took twice the time I planned to invest in it, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish the essentials version in May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: small March update</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:19:32 +0900</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2018/03/godot-course-update-6/</guid>
      <description>The new update is out! As announced in the last news post, it&amp;rsquo;s smaller than usual. for two reasons:
 I moved to Japan, took some time off and had a lot to do to settle down I caught a cold and worked slower than usual for the past 10 days. Over the past week I barely had any voice at all  Work has still been busy until the end of the month: it not only took a while to get back to everyone, catch up with activity on GitHub, but also to get back up to speed in a foreign country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>