<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kickstarter on GDquest</title>
    <link>http://gdquest.com/tags/kickstarter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kickstarter on GDquest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:29:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gdquest.com/tags/kickstarter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 course: Hobby and Indie versions out in early access</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/godot-3-course-hobby-indie-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:29:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/11/godot-3-course-hobby-indie-out/</guid>
      <description>The new version is finally out! You will find improvements and an extra video in the Finite State Machine chapter, and a new Game Design chapter. This one includes 3 html-based course documents and 40 minutes of video.
The missing two versions of the course are now out on Gumroad:
 Hobby , for hobbyists with some game creation experience, who&amp;rsquo;d like a deeper dive in Godot 3 Indie , for independent developers and students  Disclaimer: I can&amp;rsquo;t produce videos for the main chapters until Godot 3 beta is out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot 3 Close and Ranged Attack Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/godot-3-alpha-attack-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 08:10:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/godot-3-alpha-attack-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Last week we did a tutorial about attack mechanics in collaboration with Heartbeast. I got important feedback from you, the backers, and wanted to apply it to a self-contained tutorial. Consider it as a bonus while we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for Godot 3 beta.
Close combat attack:
 Weapon Animation  Weapon collision programming   Heartbeast&amp;rsquo;s tutorial:
 Ranged attack: fireball   It shows some of Godot&amp;rsquo;s strengths:
 Inherited scenes act as a base class that child scenes derive from, but you control it all through the editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for Godot 3: Why There Was No Course Update in September</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 09:03:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/10/why-no-course-update-september/</guid>
      <description>Godot 3 is coming out much later than planned. Alpha 2 isn&amp;rsquo;t even out yet. This means breaking changes keep happening on the engine. In the past few weeks alone there were important improvements to 2D physics and the UI system. The devs even renamed _fixed_process to _physics_process. Today I finished a long UI design tutorial only to learn a new Layout menu just arrived.
  This tutorial will show you how to create a flexible GUI in Godot   If I produced gameplay programming videos now for the course, they&amp;rsquo;d soon become obsolete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Kickstarter: When and How you’ll get your Rewards</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/07/godot-kickstarter-rewards-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/07/godot-kickstarter-rewards-info/</guid>
      <description>You will get all your rewards, votes and major news via email, starting this week. So be sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve set the right address on Kickstarter. Feel free to send me a message on Kickstarter or an email if you have any trouble. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to:
 Add nathan[at]gdquest.com to your contacts Check your spam folder if you didn&amp;rsquo;t get anything on Sunday  When you will get your access keys Discord: check out the email you got to access the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot Course Kickstarter Next Monday</title>
      <link>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:18:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>nathan@gdquest.com (Nathan Lovato)</author>
      <guid>http://gdquest.com/post/2017/news/godot-kickstarter-next-monday/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to become a better game developer? Gdquest will be on Kickstarter next week, to fund the creation of a game creation course for the new Godot game engine. More precisely for Godot 3, which will be out this summer!
I’m doing it with the devs&amp;rsquo; support: Rémi (akien) followed the project since the very beginning and ensured the project will be as good as it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>